Guide to the RIDGE Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- SUSTAINABLE FORESTRY AND LAND USE, 1938, 1980-2013; 1980-2013; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 1/14-27, 2/33, 3/5-7, 4/4-11, 4/13-16, 4/18-22, 5/1, 5/7-9, 5/11, 5/13-14, 5/18, 5/32, 8/2-6, 8/8, 8/16-17, 8/29-32, 9/2-5, 10, OS Folder 1-2, Tube 1-3, Tube 5)
  - Sustainable Forestry Working Groups and Coalitions, 1987-2000; Subseries A (Box-folder 4/13-16, 4/18-22, 5/7, 5/9, 5/11, 5/14)
    - Sustainable Forestry Roundtable, 1990 April (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Sustainable Forestry Roundtable and Correspondence to Members, 1990 February 22-July 10 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Draft Proposals, Correspondence, Charts, and Notes, 1990 May 14-1990 October 23 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Washington State Senate Bill 5616, Washington State House Bill 1923, Press Releases, Notes, and Letters of Support, 1990 October 10-1991 February 11 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Sustainable Forestry Roundtable Notes, Proposals, Tables, and Charts, 1987 August-1990 June 10 (Box-folder 4/18)
      Contains rate of forest harvest, watershed hydrology information, draft proposals and analysis of proposals
    - Sustainable Forestry Roundtable Working Group (1 of 2), 1987-1990 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Sustainable Forestry Roundtable Working Group (2 of 2), 1987-1990 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Susan Willis Johnson: Rate of Harvest, Uneven-Age Management, Tables and Charts, Proposals, and Washington State Regulations Regarding Non-Industrial Forest Stewardship on Private Land, 1990 February 1-July 5 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Sustainable Forestry Roundtable Summit Meeting, 1990 June 25-August 28 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Forest Practices and the Timber Fish and Wildlife [TFW] Process, approximately 1990 (Box-folder 5/7)
      Contains oversize topographic maps. Also contains information about RIDGE forest practices appeal involving land in the L.T. Murray Recreation Area
    - Forest Practices Bill, Mailing Lists, Meeting Sign-In Sheet and Notes, approximately 1989-2000 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Sustain: Coalition of Forest Sustainability Group Correspondence, Mailing Lists, Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1989 November 27-1990 April 17 (Box-folder 5/11)
      "Sustain" was a coalition of organizations aimed at reforming forest practices regulations on private land in Washington State. Sustain was mostly a collection of smaller organizations, though some larger organizations were also members
    - Sustain: Coalition of Forest Sustainability Groups, 1990 February 24-October 6 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Kittitas City and Kittitas County Planning and Politics, 1994-2009; Subseries B (Box-folder 1/14-27, 4/4, 5/1, 5/32, 8/8, 8/30, 10)
    - Paula Thompson's Campaigns, approximately 2008-2009 (Box-folder 1/14)
      Paula Thompson ran for Kittitas County District 2 County Commissioner in 2008. She was a member of Kittitas County Conservation Coalition [KCCC]
    - Comprehensive Plan Amendments, 2008 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Meeting Notes and Correspondence, 2005-2007 October 6 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - RIDGE Amendments, Copy of Resolution and Letters of Recommendation, 2006 June 27-October 3 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Comprehensive Plan Bullets from 2006 Amendment, 2006 August 16-21 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - American Forest Resources and Teanaway Comprehensive Plan, 2006 June-August (Box-folder 1/19)
      The Teanaway Comprehensive Plan is in reference to Kittitas County's revision to the county's comprehensive plan after American Forest Resources [AFR] purchased Boise Cascade-owned forest land in the Teanaway Valley. AFR sought to rezone large sections of the Teanaway Valley for a Master Planned Resort/residential development. RIDGE, along with the Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife, Friends of the Teanaway and Futurewise intervened via the Kittitas County Planning Department, who decided that the rezone would require an environmental impact statement [EIS]. After the EIS was required, AFR did not pursue the proposal for rezoning, and they sold the land to the Department of Natural Resources [DNR].
    - American Forest Resources Application Materials, 2006 June 30-August 21 (Box-folder 1/20)
      Contains DVD and oversize map
    - Kittitas County Council of Governments Subcommittee and Upper Kittitas Vision Plan, 2005 March-May 31 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Resource Lands Advisory Committee, Development Rights Recommendation, and Land Use Plan, 2001-2006 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Kittitas County Conservation Coalition Correspondence, 2006 July 21 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Correspondence and Notes, 2006 May 20-June 12 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Comprehensive Plan Amendment and Newspaper Clippings, 2005 June 29-November 15 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Kittitas County Community Group, 2005 January 15-25 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Kittitas County Comprehensive Plan and Public Meeting Announcement in Cle Elum, Washington, approximately 2003-2005 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Kittitas County Development Activities Application for Trendwest, 1997 March 7 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Kittitas County Board of Commissioners Decision on Cle Elum River Property Designation as Forest Land of Long-Term Commercial Significance, 1994 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Assorted Legal Documents, Covenants, Press, and Newspaper Clippings Regarding Kittitas County Land Use, 2000-2008 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - Public Outreach Process Pre Hearings and Kittitas County Comprehensive Plan Meeting Agenda, 2006 February 14-June 1 (Box-folder 8/8)
      Contains letter from Mayor Porter of Cle Elum to Darryl Piercy of Ellensburg regarding Roslyn City Council meeting
    - Kittitas County Easement Survey Documents and Maps, approximately 2006 (Box-folder 8/30)
    - CD 5: Roslyn City Council Meeting, 2010 November 9 (Box 10)
    - CD 13-14: Roslyn City Council Meeting, 2009 November 10 (Box 10)
  - Water and Sewerage Project Materials, 1985-2013; Subseries C (Box-folder 3/5-7, 4/5-11, 5/8, 8/29, 8/31-32, 10)
    - Water Quality Monitoring (1 of 2), approximately 2006-2013 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Water Quality Monitoring (2 of 2), approximately 2006-2013 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Suncadia Water Quality Monitoring Reports, 2008 March 3-2010 May 4 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Draft of Cle Elum Regional Sewerage Facilities Plan, 2002 May (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Draft of Environmental Impact Statement, Cle Elum Regional Sewerage Facilities Plan, and Yakima River Restoration Projects, 2002 July (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Addendum to the Final Environmental Impact Statement for Cle Elum Regional Sewerage Facility and Yakima River Restoration Projects, Washington State Growth Strategies Commission Report, and Cle Elum River Properties Report, 1990-2003 (Box-folder 4/7)
      Contains Destination Resort Handbook by the Oregon Department of Land Conservation and Development
    - Photographs of Little Creek: Black and White Photograph of Vista for Thorp Mt. Lookout (1 of 4), approximately 1985-2000 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Photographs of Little Creek: Black and White Photographs (2 of 4), approximately 1985-2000 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Photographs of Little Creek: Color Photographs of Clearcutting (3 of 4), approximately 1995-2010 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Photographs of Little Creek: Color Photographs of Salmon La Sac Road/State Route 903 (4 of 4), approximately 1995-2010 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Cle Elum River Properties, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Unsigned Declaration for Existing Public Road Easement for Winston Road, Material Concerning Settlement Protecting Domerie Creek Watershed, approximately 2006 February (Box-folder 8/29)
    - Upper Cle Elum River Restoration Correspondence, Proposals, Draft Contracts, and Public Meeting Flyer, 2005 February 9-2006 August 8 (Box-folder 8/31)
    - Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife Big Creek Project Communications, Maps, and 2002 Bonneville Power Administration Review, 2001 July 27-2005 January 13 (Box-folder 8/32)
    - CD 16: Trendwest Properties: Cle Elum Urban Growth Area [UGA] Final Environmental Impact Statement, Appendix B Water Supply Technical Report Supplement, approximately 2005-2010 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings Regarding Floods, Droughts, and Land Use, 1990-2009; Subseries D (Box-folder 5/13, 8/3-5, 8/17)
    - Flooding in Autumn 1990, 1990 December (Box-folder 5/13)
      Contains road closure lists from flooding
    - Newspaper Clippings and Domerie Creek Diversion, 2003 January 16-2009 May 4 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Black Rock Dam Flyers and Newspaper Clippings, 2003 January 25-2005 May 7 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Yakima Valley Drought Newspaper Clippings, 2005 March 8-16 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Newspaper Clippings about Teanaway Solar Farm, 2008 August 26-2009 July 16 (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Land Use Proposals, Plans, Applications and Assorted Material, 1938, 1980-2009; bulk 1980-2009; Subseries E (Box-folder 2/33, 5/18, 8/2, 8/6, 8/16, 9/2-5, 10)
    - Roslyn Forest Land Stewardship Plan, 2008 July 8-2009 July 24 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Assorted Newspaper Clippings, Advertisements, Photographs, Newsletters and Flyers Related to Forest Practices and Land Use, 1990 August 23-1991 December 10 (Box-folder 5/18)
      Contains unsigned Settlement Agreement and Hitchcock Appeal, oversize newsprint, and recommendation from RIDGE to Roslyn Mayor Jack Denning and Roslyn City Council about designation of environmental officer to review actions under SEPA [State Environmental Policy Act]
    - Forest Practices Application, 2003 March 3-July 7 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Land Use Committee and Cascadia Land Conservancy Report, 2004 September 1-2009 July 16 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Forest Practices Application, Notification to the Washington State Department of Natural Resources, 2009 September 18-23 (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Maps, Photographs, and Contracts Related to Land Deeds, Northern Pacific Railway, and Plum Creek Timber Company, 1938 August 24-1988 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Petition Regarding Rate of Timber Harvest, approximately 1980-1995 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Photograph: Elum Lake on Left, Cle Elum in Middle, Ellensburg on Right, I-90 Along Bottom of Photograph [?], approximately 1985-2000 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Acreages and Photographs, approximately 1980-2000 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - CD 6: Roslyn Urban Forest Land Stewardship Plan, 2006 August 25 (Box 10)
      contact person[?] James Begley listed on exterior of CD
    - CD 7: Roslyn Urban Forest Land Stewardship Plan Draft, 2006 October 3 (Box 10)
    - CD 15: Roslyn Urban Forest Land Stewardship Plan Draft, 2007 March 6 (Box 10)
  - Oversize Maps, 1986-2013; Subseries F (Box OS Folder 1-2, Tube 1-3, Tube 5)
    - Oversize Maps, 1988-2013[?] (Box OS Folder 1)
    - Relative Stability of Soils in the Upper Yakima Basin map, 1988-2013[?] (Box OS Folder 2)
    - Laminated Map Overlays, 1988-2013[?] (Tube Tube 1)
    - Wenatchee National Forest South with Map Overlays, 1988-2013[?] (Tube Tube 2)
    - Yakima North Central Washington Region, June 1986 Edition (Tube Tube 3)
    - Wenatchee National Forest South with Map Overlays, 1988-2013[?] (Tube Tube 5)
- NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS, PROMOTIONAL MATERIAL, AND PRESS, 1977, 1984-2009; 1990-2001; SERIES 4 (Box-folder 1/28-35, 2/1-8, 2/11-13, 2/17-18, 2/20, 4/3, 4/17, 5/10, 8/23, 8/33-35, 8/37)
  Newspaper clippings, promotional material, and press regarding various RIDGE projects. Also includes newspaper clippings, resort brochures and job postings, promotional material and advertisements regarding Plum Creek Timber Company and Trendwest/MountainStar/Suncadia Resort. Oversize newsprint appears throughout the series. Additional newspaper clippings about RIDGE can be found in SERIES 2: RIDGE OFFICE FILES. Related material about Suncadia Resort can be found in SUBSERIES 6: RIDGE/SUNCADIA LITIGATION.
  - RIDGE, 1977, 1984-2009; bulk 1990-2001; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/28-35, 2/1-8, 2/11-13, 2/17-18, 2/20, 5/10)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1984 June 1-1995 March 25 (Box-folder 1/28)
      Contains oversize items and material related to Growth Management Area [GMA] Forest Appeal
    - RIDGE Press Clippings, 1994 January 5-February 1 (Box-folder 1/29)
      Contains oversize newspaper clippings
    - Newspaper Clippings and Related Materials, 1977, 2001 June 24-2005 February 5 (Box-folder 1/30)
      Contains oversize newsprint and chapter from "A Pattern Language: Towns, Buildings, Construction", Oxford University Press 1977
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1993 Sept 13-1999 February 11 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box-folder 1/32)
      Contains oversize items
    - Wall Street Journal Letter from RIDGE Committee to Editor, 1990 July 10 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1993 August 18-1999 July 22 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1993 September-1999 December 29 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Daily Record Newspapers, Ellensburg, Washington (1 of 2), 1991 November 22-27 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Daily Record Newspapers, Ellensburg, Washington (2 of 2), 1991 November 22-27 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1992 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1992 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1993-1995 April 2 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1994 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Newspaper Clippings, approximately 1988-1993 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Newspaper Clippings, approximately 1990-1995 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Press Clippings, 2004 April 27-2009 July 30 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1992 Oct 22-1994 January 19 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1993 March 4-1994 January 19 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1996 November 7-2001 February 13 (Box-folder 2/17)
      Contains oversize newsprint and RIDGE/Trendwest Agreement Capsule Summary
    - RIDGE and Plum Creek Newspaper Clippings, 1986 June 4-1994 January 13 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Flyers, 1992 January 16-1997 March 10 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Seattle Times Article, "Timber-pact Moderators Blasted for Lobbying", 1990 November 7 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Suncadia/Trendwest and Plum Creek Timber Company, 1994-2006; Subseries B (Box-folder 4/3, 4/17, 8/23, 8/33-35, 8/37)
    - Trendwest and MountainStar Resort Brochures, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Plum Creek Timber Company Press Releases and Newspaper Clipping, 1994 January 4-1995 April 6 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Suncadia News Clippings, 2009 February-July 5 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Suncadia Resort Advertisements, Reports, Job Postings, and Newspaper Clippings, 1996-2006 (Box-folder 8/33)
      Contains oversize newsprint and advertisements
    - Advertisements and Articles about Golf Resorts, 2005 July 1-October 24 (Box-folder 8/34)
    - Newspaper Clippings Regarding JELD-WEN Windows and Doors and Possible Privatization of the Oregon Institute of Technology in Klamath Falls, Oregon, approximately 2002 February (Box-folder 8/35)
      JELD-WEN Windows and Doors was owned by Richard Wendt and the Wendt family from 1960 until the company was sold to Onex Corporation in 2011 after the housing market crisis in 2007. The Wendt family were the principal owners and investors of the Suncadia Resort and several other Oregon resorts before the housing market crisis
    - Puget Sound Business Journal Article, "Golf Resort Delays Second Course", Ad Describing Preliminary Site Plan for MountainStar, approximately 2003 (Box-folder 8/37)
- GRANTS, NONPROFIT, AND INTERNAL REVENUE SERVICE [IRS] DOCUMENTS, 1988-2015; SERIES 5 (Box-folder 2/19, 2/21-24, 2/29, 2/32, 2/34, 4/12, 4/25, 5/5, 5/22-30)
  Grant materials, nonprofit applications and documentation, tax documents, and material related to RIDGE’s dissolution. Related RIDGE office material can be found in SERIES 2: RIDGE OFFICE FILES.
  When RIDGE dissolved in 2014, Futurewise absorbed RIDGE’s rights and obligations concerning the 2014 Settlement Agreement with Kittitas County over water issues. Conservation Northwest took over RIDGE’s rights and obligations related to the Roslyn Urban Forest Land Stewardship Plan. RIDGE’s cultural programs were transferred to Oyez Roslyn!, a Roslyn-based charity.
  - General, 1988-2015; Subseries A (Box-folder 2/19, 2/22-24, 2/29, 2/32, 4/12, 4/25, 5/5, 5/22-30)
    - Grant Drafts, Newspaper Clippings, Flyers, and Correspondence, 1988-1992 June 5 (Box-folder 2/19)
      Contains oversize newsprint. Also contains Bullit grant drafts and article about Plum Creek Timber Company clearcutting north of Missoula, Montana
    - Internal Revenue Service 501C3 Application, 1995 May 22-June 6 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Receipts for Legal Expenses, 2014 February 13-June 10 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Incorporation of R Town Community Organization, 2010 September 26-2011 January 23 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - RIDGE Data Universal Number System [DUNS], 2012 August 12-2015 May 4 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Tax Letters, 1995 June 19-2009 August 13 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Internal Revenue Service [IRS] Documents, 1995 June 16-2004 November 23 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Internal Revenue Service Ruling on Request for 501 ©)(3) Exemption for RIDGE, 1995 June 30 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Grants, 2001 September 19-25 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - RIDGE 501©)(4) Application and Assorted Materials, 1989 May 19-2002 February 2 (Box-folder 5/22)
      Contains color photographs of RIDGE community meeting
    - RIDGE Association Tax Documents, 1993 December 3-2005 April 8 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Grant Application Materials for Northwest Fund for the Environment, 2009 September 17-2010 November 16 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Grant Material for Northwest Fund for the Environment, 2010 February 11-June 12 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Grant Administration Materials for Northwest Fund for the Environment, 1992 October 11-2012 April 5 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - RIDGE Organizing Documents and Tax Exemption Information, 1995 June 19-30 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Tax Documents and Organization Identification Documents, 1991 February 13-2002 June 30 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Non-Profit Paperwork for RIDGE Association, 1995 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Nonprofit Corporation Annual Report, 1989 June 19-2010 June 25 (Box-folder 5/30)
  - RIDGE Dissolution, 2009-2014; Subseries B (Box-folder 2/21, 2/34)
    - RIDGE Dissolution Records, 2009 July 24-2014 October 29 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - RIDGE and Kittitas County Settlement Agreement and RIDGE Successorship, 2014 February 6-July 3 (Box-folder 2/34)
- RIDGE/SUNCADIA LITIGATION, 1923, 1988-2013; 1988-2013; SERIES 6 (Box-folder 2/25-28, 2/36, 3/1, 3/9-22, 4/1-2, 4/23, 5/20, 5/33-34, 6/1-13, 7/1-4, 7/10-15, 8/12, 8/15, 8/18-20, 8/24-28, 8/38-40, 10, Tube 4)
  Contract advice, negotiation files for RIDGE/Suncadia litigation, contract compliance auditing, correspondence, proposals, lawsuit material, and material related to the RIDGE/Suncadia Settlement Agreement including drafts, amendments and easements. Oversize maps, oversize documents and newsprint, and electronic records appear throughout the series. Land trusts related to RIDGE/Suncadia Litigation can be found in SERIES 1: LAND TRUSTS. Related material about zoning and planning can be found in SERIES 3: SUSTAINABLE FORESTRY AND LAND USE. Newspaper clippings about Suncadia Resort can be found in SERIES 4: NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS, PROMOTIONAL MATERIAL, AND PRESS.
  The 2001 RIDGE Settlement Agreement was negotiated to mitigate the impacts of development on the 7,600 acres owned by Suncadia and their secondary development in Upper Kittitas County. A Second Amendment to the Agreement was signed in 2004. Suncadia negotiated with RIDGE for modifications to address its changing development needs. In exchange, RIDGE negotiated for Suncadia’s purchase and subsequent donation of approximately 330 acres of forested lands to the city of Roslyn, now called the Roslyn Urban Forest. A Fourth Amendment to the Agreement was signed in 2006, which allowed the Master Planned Resort [MPR] to incorporate lands that were formerly the site of the Nelson Dairy. Some of these lands were added to the MPR’s buildable footprint and significant portions were added to open space managed for wildlife, habitat, and passive recreation in perpetuity as part of the Stream C Corridor that continues on to the Cle Elum River.
  RIDGE pursued additional litigation about the proposed Suncadia Resort that focused on the water rights Suncadia would need to supply the resort. RIDGE was concerned the resort would deplete the resources of the Yakima Basin. As a result of this litigation, the Department of Ecology regulated the water so that whatever water Suncadia acquired and used would be balanced out by other water left running in the stream.
  Ownership of the resort property changed hands and names several times during and before negotiations. Plum Creek Timber Company sold the MPR to Trendwest, which then became MountainStar, which then became Suncadia. All material marked “RIDGE Settlement Agreement” is in reference to the agreement that RIDGE negotiated with the owners of the resort property, regardless of who owned the property at the time.
  - RIDGE Contract Advice, 2007-2011; Subseries A (Box-folder 2/25-28)
    - RIDGE Contract Advice and Client Documents (1 of 4), 2007 March 17-2011 January 15 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - RIDGE Contract Advice and Client Documents (2 of 4), 2007 March 17-2011 January 15 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - RIDGE Contract Advice and Client Documents (3 of 4), 2007 March 17-2011 January 15 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - RIDGE Contract Advice and Client Documents (4 of 4), 2007 March 17-2011 January 15 (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Contract Compliance Auditing, 2005-2008; Subseries B (Box-folder 3/14, 7/10-15)
    - Agreement between Suncadia, Adolfson Associates, and Douglas Kilgore, 2005 May 9 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Adolfson Associates Inc.,: Contract Compliance Audit for Suncadia Contract and RIDGE Settlement Agreement (1 of 2), 2005 (Box-folder 7/10)
      Contains oversize material
    - Adolfson Associates Inc.,: Contract Compliance Audit for Suncadia Contract and RIDGE Settlement Agreement (2 of 2), 2005 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Adolfson Associates Inc.,: Contract Compliance Audit for Suncadia Contract and RIDGE Settlement Agreement, 2007 (Box-folder 7/12)
      Contains oversize material. Some material in the folder may be referred to as "The Matrix", a list of topics analyzed and verified by Adolfson Associates during the contract compliance audit of the RIDGE Settlement Agreement
    - Adolfson Associates Inc.,: Contract Compliance Audit for Suncadia Contract and RIDGE Settlement Agreement, 2005 October 14-2007 January 17 (Box-folder 7/13)
      Contains CD-rom and oversize material. Some material in the folder may be referred to as "The Matrix", a list of topics analyzed and verified by Adolfson Associates during the contract compliance audit of the RIDGE Settlement Agreement
    - Adolfson Associations Inc.,: Contract Compliance Audit for Suncadia Contract, Suncadia Information, Meeting Notes, Charts, and Correspondence, 2005 December 3-2008 November 1 (Box-folder 7/14)
      Some material in the folder may be referred to as "The Matrix", a list of topics analyzed and verified by Adolfson Associates during the contract compliance audit of the RIDGE Settlement Agreement
    - Suncadia Landscape Review with Contract Compliance Auditor, 2008 August 12-September 5 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Settlement Drafts, Agreements, Amendments, and Easements, 1991-2010; bulk 2000-2010; Subseries C (Box-folder 3/9-13, 3/15-22, 4/1-2, 5/33-34, 6/11-13, 7/1-4, 8/19-20, 10)
    - First Amendment of RIDGE Settlement Agreement and Second Agreement for MountainStar Master Planned Resort [MPR], 2003 March 13-2004 April 19 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Original RIDGE Settlement Agreement (1 of 2), 2004 May 1 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Original RIDGE Settlement Agreement (2 of 2), 2004 May 1 (Box-folder 3/11)
      Contains oversize enlargements of site plans
    - Cooperative Agreement (1 of 2), 2003 April 1-2004 December (Box-folder 3/12)